Mohammad Ali Jafarzadeh, MBA

Freelancer Management Consultant in Finance, HR, & Admin.

Mobile: +٩٨ ٩١٢ ١٤٤٨٤٦١, email: m.a.jafarzadeh٦٨@gmail.com, Shahrake Gharb, Tehran, Iran, ٥٢, Married

CAREER SUMMARY

A versatile professional with Y years of experience, having BA in accounting from

Shahid Beheshty and MBA from Tehran both State Universities. I am enjoying expert knowledge of all local labor regulations, Social Security Organization (SSO) laws and Iranian tax laws including VAT, CIT, WHT and PIT. Have the distinction in problem solving. Honored for the membership of the Board of Arbitration with the right to vote constituted by the Labor Office.

Experience included working as Chief Accountant, Finance Manager, Finance Director, HR & Admin Manager and Country Supporting Manager and Branch Manager.

The detailed responsibilities discharged as above-mentioned titles included but not limited to:

The détailed responsibilities discharged as above-mentioned titles included but not limited to:

A - Operational Methods and Procedures: Amend the accounting division's structure and organization chart. Correct the way of operating the purchases department and warehouses.

Plan for reconciliation of statistics produced by different production lines. Plan to optimize and change the methods and procedures in other departments.

Conduct the audit committee and plan for independent audit of the year. Plan internal audit operations and remove the internal weak points. Audit the sales and local purchase and control the accurate running of the contracts.

B - Cost Accounting Issues: Permanent control on receiving production information, information updates of warehouses and collecting information for distribution of service cost centers.

Supervise the update of the information of BOM and the specifications of packed and unpacked products.

Analyze the changes in costs, profitability of products and other information.

C - Budgeting and Reporting: Prepare the annual operational plans in coordination with other managers. Prepare the operational budget, capital expenditures budget and cash budget for the year.

Supervise preparation of the "receipts and payments" and "changes in shareholder's current account" statements. Supervise preparation of the "comparative reports of operations and budgets".

Control the company's commitments and submitting it to the board.

D - Financial Accounting Issues: Control and approve the payment vouchers, cheques issuing forms. Control all payments. Control PDCs and other installments due date lists.

Handle bank accounts and bank reconciliation. Handle payments of statuary payments and other installments on time and preventing the fines.

Plan and supervise preparation of financial statements. Solve problems. Train staff in practical cases.

Supervise the reconciliation of the accounts between the company and third parties.

Control recording of the accrued expenses. Control renewal of all insurance contracts on time.

Control and ensure accurate and on time recording of sales. Control and ensure all JVs.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Jan. Y.IA - Sep. Y.th. Y.Y. - Managing Director, SNS Iranian, Tehran, Iran

Aug. Y. Y. - May, Y. Y. - Branch Manager, Finance HR & Admin Mngr., CSE Transtel, Tehran, Iran http://cse-transtel.com/, As Branch Manager:



To develop forecasts, maintains office services by organizing office operations and procedures; controlling correspondence: designing filing systems; assigning and monitoring clerical functions.

Managing and overseeing branch personnel, supervising branch operations, and ensuring efficient operation on a day-to-day basis, providing training, and motivation for staff and evaluate staff's work performance.

To maintain office staff by recruiting, selecting, orienting, and training employees and site frequent visits and interaction with jobsites, employees and customers.

Track down to collect overdue debts from clients and in parallel trying to secure new contracts.

And as Finance HR and Admin Manager:

- 1) Assist the general branch manager for preparation of annual office budget and manage the branch resources within the approved budget.
- Y) Provision of management and monitoring activities of branch staff.
- r) Organize applicant's Interview for recruitment, orientation of new employees to the office environment, company's policy, safety and training programs as deems appropriate.
- ٤) Supervision of office employees' performances in order to prevent nonconformity with regards to company's policy, procedures, and prescribed standards.
- °) Preparation of on time Iran branch monthly and project expense report to head office.
- 1) Prepare annual appraisal performance report of employees, for records, possible annual pay increase, promotion, reward, Transfer and etc.
- Y) Purchasing office supplies required for day to day operation.
- A) Being involved in travel desk tasks such as obtaining visa, work permits for expatriates.

Country Support Manager, SNS Iranian, Tehran, Iran May 7.11 - Jul. 7.17

https://snsiran.com/, Ebrahim Rezaieazdeh: +٩٨٩١٢٧٦٣٥٨٠٧, Joined the company as Finance, HR and Admin manager and got promoted to CSM in the middle of the probation period and in \ month saved more than Y · · K USD on claimed tax.



Aug. Y. 1. - May Y. 11 Head of Accounting, Kayson (Daelim, Kayson, Sazeh JV) - Tehran, Iran

https://www.kayson-ir.com/ . Head of Accounting for the large sized joint venture through Daelim, Kayson, Sazeh of EPC contract for the LNG project.

Controlling accounting and adhering to all underlying procedures for payroll, warehouse, cost and general accounting. Managing tax and SSO issues and dealing with auditors and tax assessors. Managing revenues and producing reports. Preparing budget and other required reports to facilitate monitoring the actual performance and investigate variances. Financial analysis; Review the contracts and negotiating with subcontractors prior to signing the contract to clear financial requirements.

Jan. Y. . . - Aug. Y. . . - Project Finance Manager, Namvaran Consulting Engineers (NCE), Tehran, Iran http://www.namvaran.ir/, Morteza Ghashghai: +1/4/1/19/04/19, Main responsibilities included checking the

subcontractors invoicing and processing payment. Preparing the tracking sheet for all the payments to the subcontractors for and monitoring purposes.

Jun. Y. A. - Jan. Y. A. CFO, Hormuz Petrochemical Company, Tehran Iran

The project involves construction of a petrochemicals plant in Hormuz with a production capacity of \(\) million tons Urea and Ammonia per year but Due to the uncertain status of the land, the project was suspended until \(\) and that's why I left the company.

Interviewed by OOC authorities and qualified to play the role of CFO and was responsible for preparation of financial statements and reports, and arranging audit and AGM required documents.

Jun. Y. Y. - Jun. Y. A. Country Finance Manager, Axiom Telecom Co., Tehran, Iran

https://www.axiomtelecom.com/, Achievements included completing all the work to establish office facilities and to implement accounting and reporting software of the company.



Aug. Y. . . - Jun. Y. . V CFO, Afagh Mihan Nava Int'l Trading Co., Tehran, Iran,

http://www.decra-iran.com/, Safa Kafaeian: +1/41/1//// Successfully obtained clean audit report. Handled tax and SSO and maintained good relations with bank to open Letter of Credits in unfavorable situations.

Apr. Your - Aug. Your Financial Manager, Noritazeh Glass Manufacturing Co., Tehran, Iran http://www.noritazeh.com/, CFO Responsibilities. Key achievement included successful recovery of huge amount of Insurance claim resulted due to fire broke in the yard.

Aug. Y · · · - Jan. Y · · · E Chief Accountant, Well Services of Iran (Schlumberger Methods) Tehran, Bushehr &

Schlumberger

https://www.wsi-oilfield.com/, Handle all internal contracts, controls, payments and bank relations. Successfully implement Schlumberger systems and procedure on both base locations (Bushehr and Ahwaz)

Jul. 1997 - Jul. 1997 Head of Accounting, Andrade Gutierrez S.A (AGSA), Tehran, Iran

http://www.andradegutierrez.com.br/, I was head of Accounting for the World Bank funded project of Y...
million USD of Tehran Municipality use to take care of all financial affairs including dealing with Tax and SSO authorities.

Apr. 1994 - May 1997 Head of Accounting, Farbal Construction Co., Bandar Abbas, Iran

Reza Mafi: +1/11/1//// , I was mainly active in hiring and firing the manpower, payroll, termination benefits and attending in Board of Arbitration to resolve the disputes between employee and employer.

1997 - 1995 Iranian Audit Organization, Iran Mash'hood Auditing Firm, Tehran, Iran



ANDRADE

GUTIERREZ

http://en.azpar.com/ , Abbas Vafadar CEO: +٩^٩٩٣٥٩٨٨٨٨٨, +٩^٧١٨٨٥٤٤٥٩٠-٢, I have worked as an auditor in companies active in various fields of activities.

EDUCATION

Sep 19AA - Mar 1997 Shahid Beheshty State University

Tehran, Iran

Accounting, Bachelor(BSc/BA), GPA BA

Apr ۲۰۰۷ - Apr ۲۰۰۸

Tehran University

Tehran University Tehran, Iran

General, MBA, GPA MS, Qualified for ACCA

OTHER CERTIFICATES

Budgeting IMI, Iran Y · · · V
QHSE Schlumberger, Iran Y · · · V

COMPUTER SKILLS: MS Office Tools as well as local and international accounting software and ERPs

LANGUAGES

English Fluent
 Turkish Native
 Arabic Basic

Apart from financial experiences, I have experience in below issues in international and local companies:

-)) Preparing tax appeals, attending in TDSB meetings, obtaining tax clearance & SSO FCC
- Obtaining bank facilities, loans and opening Letter of Credits
- Preparing employment, lease and commercial contracts, and RFQs
- f) Preparing bilingual financial statements respecting the IFRS and the local standards.
- o) Opening LCs considering the embargo law, obtaining and managing BGs
 Negotiating with local / international authorities in financing process
- γ) Furnishing the office for a startup company from a to z
- A) Obtaining visa and work permit and help desk affairs for expatriates
- 1) Having practical experience in office and branch registration process
- 1.) Having successful experience in collecting pending receivables from the clients